closetlondon.com 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy

This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you use our website. In collecting this information, we are acting as a data controller and, by law, we are required to provide you with information about us, about why and how we use your data, and about the rights you have over your data. 

We are Closet London Limited. Our address is Unit 1 Ground Floor, 36-40 Copperfield Road London E3 4RR. You can contact us by post at the above address, by email at [dpo@closetlondon.com](mailto:dpo@closetlondon.com) or by telephone on +44 (0)203 859 8887.

When you use our website

When you submit an enquiry via our website

When you purchase a product from our website

When you sign up to receive our newsletter

When you download a sample document

When you submit a review about us

When you take part in our feedback survey

Your rights as a data subject

Your right to complain

Updates to this privacy policy

When you use our website to browse our products and view the information we make available, a number of cookies are used by us and by third parties to allow the website to function, to collect useful information about visitors and to help to make your user experience better. 

**Cookie Policy**

**1) Cookies and similar technologies**

A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your computer or electronic device when you access our website. Similar technologies include web beacons, action tags, local shared objects ('flash cookies') and single-pixel gifs. Such technologies can be used to track users' actions and activities, and to store information about them.

This website also uses technologies such as web beacons and pixels. These are other technologies that store information in your browser or device, using local shared objects or local storage.

**  
2) Information collected**

The information we obtain from our use of cookies will not usually contain your personal data. While we may obtain information about your computer or any other electronic device which you use to access our website, such as your IP address, your browser and/or other internet log information, this information will not usually identify you personally.

In certain circumstances we may also collect personal information about you but only where you voluntarily provide it (e.g by completing an online form) or where you purchase goods or services from us.

When you access the Closet London website, we use cookies in order to create an enjoyable and easy online shopping experience for you. These are the main types of cookies that we use and why we use them:

  * Strictly necessary cookies – these cookies are required for the operation of our website. They will, for example, allow you to navigate the site, add items to your shopping basket and purchase them.
  * Targeting or advertising – these cookies are used to enhance your Closet London online experience and to deliver relevant content to you as set out in our Privacy Policy e.g. adverts or abandoned basket emails.  Such cookies also help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. These cookies may be placed by us, or by third parties (see “Advertising cookies and similar technologies” below).
  * Customer preference – to improve your shopping experience by saving you time when making a purchase. For example, we may use cookies to store your language or country so you don‘t have to set them up every time you visit our website.  
  * Site analytics – to measure and analyse how customers use our website and respond to marketing, to improve your shopping experience and to improve the overall functionality of our website.

**3) Consent for cookies**

The cookies described above may be either “session cookies”, which means they are temporary and are automatically deleted from your computer or device when you close your browser, or they may be “persistent cookies”, which last until their expiry date or until you or your browser delete them. By law, we are required to ask your permission before storing non-essential cookies on your computer. If you choose to block or delete cookies or similar technologies used on our website, it may prevent the website from functioning properly or at all.

In most cases we will need your consent in order to use cookies on this website. The exception is where the cookie is essential in order for us to provide you with a service you have requested, or essential to the inherent functionality of the website (e.g to enable you to store items in a shopping basket and/or to use our check-out process).

There is a notice on our home page which describes how we use cookies and which also provides a link to our website privacy policy. If you use this website after this notification has been displayed to you, we will assume that you consent to our use of cookies for the purposes described in this website cookie policy and our website privacy policy.

Please refer to our Privacy Policy for a  list of cookies we use.

**  
4) How to turn off cookies**

You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the websites below tell you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, some of our website features may not function as a result.

For further information on cookies generally visit aboutcookies.org or the Information Commissioner's webpage on cookies [ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/online/cookies/)

**5) Analytics cookies**

Our website uses cookies provided by Google Analytics. These cookies allow us to collect information in an anonymous form about engagement with our website. They tell us, for example, the number of visitors to our website, how visitors have come to our website, and the pages they visited. You can find out more about Google Analytics by visiting [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/), and you can opt-out of the use of these cookies by visiting <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**6) Advertising cookies and similar technologies**

We work with third parties including Facebook who may use cookies, web beacons and other storage technologies to collect and receive information from our website and elsewhere on the internet, and use it to provide measurement services and targeted adverts. The use of these tools can tell us when you visited our website, the pages you visited, and the links you followed. This information will be used to make advertising more relevant to your interests. The parties that place these cookies may use the information collected in accordance with their own privacy policies.  Please note that if you do block these third party tools, you will still see advertisements, but these will not be tailored to your interests.

**7) Third party cookies**

We work with some third party suppliers to enable features on our website or to improve our online advertising. These suppliers may set cookies on our website. These include:

**Supplier Name**

| 

**          What They Do**  
  
---|---  
  
Trustpilot

| 

This company helps provide the customer reviews and questions features on our product pages.  
  
Ometria

| 

They provide the system that sends out our marketing emails. They set a cookie that helps us monitor our emails and how many people open and click on them. You will only receive our emails if you have signed up to our database. You can unsubscribe by clicking on the unsubscribe link in any email.  
  
Bronto

| 

They provide the system that sends out our marketing emails. They set a cookie that helps us monitor our emails and how many people open and click on them. You will only receive our emails if you have signed up to our database. You can unsubscribe by clicking on the unsubscribe link in any email.  
  
Google Display Network

| 

Google uses cookies to provide you with personalised adverts when you visit other selected websites. They compile anonymous statistics on what you have looked at and in some cases bought.  
  
Criteo and Google Adwords

| 

We advertise on the search engines run by these companies. Their cookies enable us to see if anyone buys any of our products as a result. None of the information contained in these cookies identifies you personally.  
  
Facebook Tag

| 

Using the Facebook tag we’re able to target relevant audiences of people who have visited our website and remarket to people who show an interest in products. None of the information contained in these cookies identifies you personally.  
  
Facebook / Twitter

| 

If you ‘share’ Closet London content on social networks through the links on our pages, you may be sent cookies from these websites. We don’t control these cookies, so for more information on them please see the third-party websites such as Facebook or Twitter.  
  
Affiliate Window

| 

We work with Affiliate Window on our Affiliate program. We need this information to determine a sale and commission correctly. We do not capture any personal information of any customers. The information we capture is related to Order ID, SKU number, Transaction time and date, Process time and date, Sale amount, product type etc.  
  
Mention Me

| 

Refer-a-friend scripts – allowing us to track new customers and reward them with a promotional code.  
  
Zendesk

| 

This script works for our customer services team and is present on FAQs, Contact us and supporting pages. Direct Contact forms on ZenDesk (the Customer Services helpdesk), serve enough personal information to allow our customer service agents to establish a direct communication.  
  
Loyalty Lion

| 

We work with Loyalty Lion as part of our customer loyalty program, which allows us to reward our regular customers.  
  
Amazon

| 

It allows Closet London to offer an additional payment method for our customers i.e. payment through the customer’s Amazon account  
  
Hotjar

| 

Allows Closet London to try out different website improvements and report on their effectiveness.  
  
Nosto

| 

Allows Closet London to provide a personalised customer experience through personal recommendations on the homepage, product listing pages and product pages.  
  
SLI

| 

These cookies are needed to use our onsite search functionality and measure its efficiency  
  
  **8) Changes to cookies policy**

We may change this Cookies Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of this policy, and in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice such as adding a statement to the homepage of the website or sending you an email with the update. Please check this Cookies Policy regularly to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

When you submit an enquiry via our website, we ask you for your name, contact telephone number and email address.

We use this information to respond to your query, including providing you with any requested information about our products and services. We may also email you several times after your enquiry in order to follow up on your interest and ensure that we have answered it to your satisfaction. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in providing accurate information prior to a sale.

Your enquiry is stored and processed as an email which is hosted by Microsoft within the European Economic Area (EEA).

It is also logged on a CRM system on a cloud server based in the United Kingdom, a country which the EU says has adequate data protection laws in place to protect your data. ** **

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

We keep enquiry emails for two years, after which they are securely archived and kept for seven years, when we delete them. CRM records are kept for three years after the last contact with you and are then archived.

When you purchase products from us online, we ask you for your name, address, contact telephone number, email address and credit card information. We also record your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the Internet. 

We will use your information to verify your credit card details for your purchase, process your order and to send you your products. We will also send you a receipt via email and we may use your telephone number to contact you regarding your purchase.

We require this information in order to process your payment, deliver your products and fulfil our contract with you. We record your IP address in order to show that the correct tax was applied to the sale, which we are required to do by law.

Your information is stored on our website and on our cloud server, both of which are based within the European Union. Your credit card details are passed to a third-party payment processor which is based in the UK and retains its data within the European Union.

We do not retain your credit card information.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

We keep your order information for an indefinite period, as we may need to refer back to this information.

When you sign up to receive our newsletter, we ask for your name and your email address. 

We will ask for your consent to use your name and email address to email you our newsletter which contains information about our products and other information which we feel might be of interest to you.

You can withdraw your consent at any time and we will stop sending you the newsletter. ** **

Your name and email address are shared with a third-party mailing system which is based in the UK. This company has contractually committed to providing appropriate safeguards for your personal data which means it will be protected in line with the legal requirements of the European Union.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you. 

We keep your personal data for as long as we produce and distribute our newsletter. If you withdraw your consent, we will mark your details so that they are not used and delete them after three years.

When you request to download something from our website, we ask for your name, company name (which is optional) and your email address.

We use this information to email you a link to download the requested information. We may also email you after your download in order to follow up on your interest in our products. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing to prospects for our products.

Your name and email address are shared with a third-party mailing system which is based in the UK. This company has contractually committed to providing appropriate safeguards for your personal data which means it will be protected in line with the legal requirements of the European Union.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for one year after you requested your download, after which it is deleted.

### **_ _**

When you submit a review about us we record your name, your email address and your IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is the address of your computer on the Internet.

We use this information to provide verified independent views about our products to potential customers. Your name and the content of your review (but not your email address or IP address) may be publicly displayed on our website. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing our products and services.

Your details are shared with a third-party reviews system which is based within the European Economic Area (EEA).

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for as long as we are marketing the product or services that the review refers to, after which it is deleted. You may ask us to remove your review at any time.

When you take part in our feedback survey, we record your name, your email address, your organisation name, your job role and your answers to questions we ask about your opinion of, and use of, our products.

We use this information to develop and improve our products and our customer relationships. Your information and your comments may be publicly displayed on our website as a testimonial. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing our products.

Your details are shared with a third-party surveys system which is based within the European Economic Area (EEA).

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for two years, or for as long as we are marketing the product or services that the review refers to, whichever is shorter. You may ask us to remove a testimonial that is based on your feedback from our website at any time.

By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate. If we have asked for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw that consent at any time.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or to fulfil a contract, you can ask us to give you a copy of the information in a machine-readable format so that you can transfer it to another provider.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or legitimate interest, you can request that your data be erased.

You have the right to ask us to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully.

Finally, in some circumstances you can ask us not to reach decisions affecting you using automated processing or profiling.

To submit a request regarding your personal data by email, post or telephone, please use the contact information provided above in the Who Are We section of this policy.

If you have a complaint about our use of your information, we would prefer you to contact us directly in the first instance so that we can address your complaint. However, you can also contact the Information Commissioner’s Office via their website at [www.ico.org.uk/concerns](https://www.ico.org.uk/concerns) or write to them at:

Information Commissioner's Office

Wycliffe House

Water Lane

Wilmslow

Cheshire

SK9 5AF

We regularly review and, if appropriate, update this privacy policy from time to time, and as our products and use of personal data evolves. If we want to make use of your personal data in a way that we haven’t previously identified, we will contact you to provide information about this and, if necessary, to ask for your consent.
